Harold Blake Walker Papers
Harold Blake Walker Papers
1959-1966
Walker, Harold Blake.
1 linear ft.
American Presbyterian clergyman. Collection contains manuscripts, memorabilia and published books.
3175653
Biographical History
Harold Blake Walker (d. 2002) was an American Presbyterian clergyman and author. He was was the senior pastor of the First Presbyterian Church of Evanston, Illinois for many years, and his column, "Living Faith," appeared in the Chicago Tribune and other newspapers from 1954 to 1975.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Harold Blake Walker Papers contains manuscripts, memorabilia and published books.
Arrangement of the Collection
No particular order.
Related Material
has extensive holdings relating to Presbyterian and Methodist church and clergy. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; Walker, Harold Blake.; Presbyterian Church -- Clergy.; Christian literature, American.; Devotional literature, American.; Clergy as authors -- United States.; Manuscripts for publication.; Prayers.; Sermons.; Clergy.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Harold Blake Walker, 1967.
Inventory
- Books
  - Harold Blake Walker / Faith for Times of Tension, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Harold Blake Walker / Prayers to Live By, Chicago, Aspley House, circa 1966 (Box 1)
  - Harold Blake Walker / Thirty Selected Sermons, reprinted from the Chicago Tribune Magazine, circa 1966 (Box 1)
  - Harold Blake Walker / To Conquer Loneliness, New York, Harper and Row, circa 1966 (Box 1)
  - Harold Blake Walker / Venture of Faith: A Guide to Marriage and the Home, New York, Harper Bros., circa 1959 (Box 1)
- Memorabilia
  - Dedication of the Harold Blake Walker Chapel Youth Building Music Room, First Presbyterian Church, Chicago, 3 Jun 1962 (Box 1)
- Manuscripts
  - To conquer loneliness, circa 1966; typescript (Box 1)